$10, please.
Oh, man.
Sleep, little dumpling.
I have replaced your mother!
Aw.
Oh, my God!
Robot deely-boppers!
And there's a robot scratching post!
You should try it out, Bender.
Please, I have some dignity.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my killbot features Lotus Notes
and a machine gun.
It is the finest available.
Like fun it is, you glass-headed wallaby!
No one calls me that!
I'm having at you!
Wernstrom!
Such senseless aggression.
Come on, let's go for a paddleboat ride.
The secret was scratching
really, really hard!
And now, the woman
who "Mom"- opolizes the robot industry...
I get it!
Oh, now I get it.
Hello, dearies.
Whoo! I love that old bat!
Ladies and gentlemen,
for the 17th year in a row,
the future of robotics has arrived.
Boys?
I give you Robot 1-X!
Ow!
Oh.
Neat.
Quite frankly, Robot 1-X
will put all my previous models to shame.
Incidentally, would one
of my previous models mind coming up here?
Right here. I'm coming.
Come on, baby. I'll do it.
Jerk.
Here we go.
I'm your top-of-the-line, Mom.
Notice that this obsolete robot
runs on alcohol and emits pollution
whereas Robot 1-X runs on pollution
and emits pure oxygen
with a fresh pine scent.
Man, that smells great!
Now let's see how both robots
do at a typical household task,
sorting a jar of pocket change.
Task completed.
Total value, $4.73 and one Albanian lek.
Very good, Robot 1-X.
And you, bending unit?
Uh, I never got the change.
Suckers.
Presenting Mom's Friendly Robots!
That new robot is great, huh?
He sure made me look like a pile of crap.
Indeed. That's why
I bought one to help around the office.
Let's try him out.
Robot 1-X, can you clean
Nibbler's stanky litter box?
I can and will.
Hey, I could've done that
if you'd asked me!
I asked you five minutes ago.
You call that a kiss?
I'll show you!
Come here, Nibbler!
Oh, look, Bender,
if you want something to do
stop making out and give us a hand.
Here. Go up on the roof
and install this fake satellite dish
so we can impress the neighbors.
Yes, sir! I'm on it!
Oh, and have Robot 1-X help you.
Gah!
Get out of here, freshman!
I don't need your help.
Our owners asked me to assist you.
Yeah? Well, assist this!
Help!
When I screamed help, I didn't mean you!
I apologize.
However, I was able to do your job
before I saved your life.
Don't mind me.
I'm just saving you the trouble
of throwing me away.
Spleesh! Mell out, Bender.
Come watch some TV.
I can't. I'm stuck in the can.
Well, ask Robot 1-X to pull you out.
Never!
Why can't you accept his help?
I hate him!
But he's just a tool
to make your life easier.
Like a socket wrench or a burglar's kit.
I can't ask for his help because...
Yes?
I'm scared of him.
Oh, sorry.
Well, then, there's only one solution.
You need an upgrade to make you
compatible with
Robot 1-X's new technology.
An upgrade?
But I thought we all agreed I was perfect!
Fry, didn't we agree I was perfect?
Oh, yeah, no, you're pretty perfect.
"Pretty" perfect?
So, you do think I need an upgrade.
Yes, for God's sakes, yes!
Fine. I'll be back in a few days.
Man, I hate those new 1-X robots.
I'd like to stab 'em.
Give 'em some of these!
Yeah! Right on, nutcake!
Parole officer says I got to upgrade
or he won't give me back
my stabbin' knife.
But it's no big.
I bate those 1-Xs so much,
I know it won't affect me.
Death to the 1-X robots!
I love those magnificent 1-X robots!
The 1-X robots are my friends.
Wait! What happened
to your enthusiasm for stabbing them?
I'm past that.
Later, blood!
It's like he's not him anymore.
You took away his robo-humanity!
I changed my mind!
Ooh!
Yeah, I did it!
I escaped!
But to what kind of a life?
I'm too scared to get the upgrade,
but I can't face my friends
again without it.
And so, I set sail for unknown shores.
Oh, merciful Poseidon, take pity
on this mechanical mariner!
Oh, geez.
Curse you, merciful Poseidon!
Boy, what is the deal with the ocean?
A tropical island, huh?
Well, I've washed up in worse places.
Okay, first up, I'm gonna
need to build a shelter.
There.
Well, I guess I'll go out for a while.
Damn! One rock short of rescue.
Oop, low on power.
Better fuel up.
Ah, no!
Guess I'll do what I always do
when I run out of booze.
Okay, don't panic.
I've got these yams.
I'll just make some yam schnapps.
Hmm...
Hey, I should be mad at you!
Now turn around.
Beer!
Ow!
Who are you and why should I care?
Side A... We're a community
of outdated robots
who refused to upgrade and came here...
Side B ...to live a simpler existence
free of technology.
A working cartridge unit?
Wow, you guys went obsolete years ago.
Your mother.
What Cartridge Unit means
is the very things that make us obsolete
also make us unique.
I, for example, need to keep
refilling my water wheel
or I'll power down forever.
Oh, God, I'll never make it this time!
This is the end!
Anyway, we like it here.
Like you have a choice.
So what's your problem?
Not enough...
Memory?
Oh, great. Now I remember that word,
but I forgot my wife's face.
Oh, God, no! I want to live!
If you'd like,
you're welcome to join our society.
Look, no offense, but I need technology,
especially e-mail and snowmobiles
and television.
Without television,
how will I know what's buzzworthy?
Why would you want to watch TV
when you can watch a snail crawl
for hours on end?
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Oh, man, he's never going to
make it over that next pebble.
Wait... Wait...
Oh, my God! He made it!
Yeah, way to go!
Whoo-hoo!
That was the greatest thing ever.
Let's party.
I'm all right
Nobody's worried about me...
Yeah, baby, come on!
Where did you get that CD?
It's one of my 10 desert island discs.
I never really thought
I'd get to use them,
but look at me now.
Ooh, yeah, baby, do that dance.
CDs are unnatural.
Why don't you just listen to the ocean?
Which ocean? That ocean?
Wow. It's like the Earth making
sweet, salty love to itself
while all the fish groove on it.
So much for this garbage.
Take that, Beethoven, you deaf bastard.
Bang, bang, bang.
You sure got this life thing figured out,
cymbal-banging monkey.
Hi, Bender.
We know how much you miss technology
so we brought you this washing machine
that drifted ashore.
Ooh, I'm going to wash my linen so hard...
- I don't understand.
- Huh?
Wretched technology has brought me
nothing but misery.
But, Bender, you are technology.
You're the most advanced thing
on this entire island.
Oh, it's true.
I am a hideous triumph
of form and function,
but not for long.
Ow! Ooh! Ee!
Oh!
Oh! Ow, that hurts. Oh, ooh...
The downgrade is complete.
Behold my handcrafted purity.
The modern world can bite
my splintery, wooden ass.
Ah...
Welcome to your new life
of simple tranquility.
Forget that.
I say the whole world must learn
of our peaceful ways...
By force.
What?
We're going back to civilization
to wage war on technology!
What?
Row, comrades, row!
We'll soon stage an attack on technology
worthy of being chronicled
in an anthem by Rush.
We've been sailing for three weeks.
Maybe I should check
our position with the periscope.
Aye-yo!
Mirrors reflecting mirrors!
Hi-tech sorcery!
Sorcery, I say!
Did you see anything?
Yep, we're there.
Prepare to surface!
And now technology shall taste
the lash of the hickory switch!
Technology is defeated.
Let us return to the island
and celebrate by counting rocks.
- Yes!
- Yay!
Whoa, whoa.
No one wants to count rocks more than me,
but our mission is not complete.
Not so long as Robot 1-X torments me
with his obvious superiority.
Ready the catapult, Sinclair!
Aim for their power lines.
They're the devil's veins
and electricity is his blood.
Bender, if we don't survive the attack,
I want you to know I love you.
Okay, fine. Fire!
Oh, I'm blind!
Professor, we have no power.
What do you mean, no power?
We're living in the future.
I'd better light some candles.
Friends, I've come to free you
from your complicated lives!
Free you from the complicated part,
I mean,
not the lives part.
Oh, Lord, he's made of wood.
What now, Bender?
I got a downgrade.
I'm a steam-powered wooden robot
just as nature intended.
Therefore, I must kill Robot 1-X.
That's just stupid.
Does Mr. Bender wish me to destroy myself?
I don't need your charity.
Target Robot 1-X and fire.
You wanged my ship,
you walnut-paneled idiot!
Try again, Sinclair!
I said target Robot 1-X.
Who's Robot 1-X? Launching!
So, I guess everything worked out fine.
Great, now we're being crushed.
Help us, wooden Bender!
Ah! Those guys hate fire!
I got to do something.
What the... Termites?
Well, I don't need legs
to save my friends.
I'll just use the old extenso-matic arms.
Bender, hurry! This fuel's expensive!
Also, we're dying!
I'm a-coming.
Ow! Lousy primitive body!
Oh, why didn't I get that upgrade?
I'm an outdated piece of junk.
Sir, might I recommend...
You shut up!
No, wait. I can use you
as a tool to save my friends
and I'll still be the hero
who everyone says how great he was.
How may I help you?
Ah! Save my friends!
Ah! And Zoidberg!
Look, my hair got singed
into an even cuter do.
Hey, where's Bender?
Down here.
I'm so sorry, guys.
I never meant to hurt you.
Just to destroy everything
you ever believed in.
Well, at least you saved us from, uh, you.
Thank God you finally overcame
your incompatibility with Robot 1-X.
Oh, yeah, we were totally in sync.
I was, like, "Save them."
And he was all, "No problem."
And then he did it.
This new technology is great.
I love those magnificent 1-X robots.
The 1-X robots are my friends.
It's like his personality
is totally different now.
Oh, maybe this upgrade
isn't such a good idea.
I'd like to give Robot 1-X
a big smooch on the...
Hey, what's the dealio?
Your upgrade is complete.
But I destroyed the technology
of the world.
I ran on the beach and felt
the sand between my foot cups.
Everyone experiences
the upgrade differently.
Woof. If that stuff wasn't real,
how can I be sure anything is real?
Is it not possible, nay, probable
that my whole life is just a product
of my or someone else's imagination?
No. Get out. Next.
Well, I guess reality is
what you make of it.
Yep. Oh, thanks, baby.